ALLISON NICOLE DRAKE

Developer, Designer, and Maker of Things

6208 OKLAHOMA DRIVE VANCOUVER, WA 98661 (360) 567-5355

AllisonNicoleDrake@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/allisonnicoledrake

I am a passionate and tenacious learner who gets excited about data, design, and development. I design with the user in mind and use a combination of research, data analysis, observation, feedback, skill, and instinct to implement thoughtful designs that bring customers joy and businesses profit. Challenges are opportunities to solve problems and create solutions, and working with a team only gives me a greater scope of insight and knowledge to pull from and contribute to.

I have relevant industry experience in the fields of marketing, engineering, programming, product development, product design, manufacturing, shipping and logistics, human resources, sales, alternative fuels/biodiesel, online retail, inventory management, senior/aging/disability services, large scale distribution, education, craft goods and services, accounting, film and audio editing, and music production/performance. I love learning new things and making products for other people to enjoy.

Creative collaboration is welcome and encouraged! I hope to make something for you in the near future!

SKILLS + KNOWLEDGE + CHARACTERISTICS

HTML + CSS | Python | C# | .NET | SQL | Database Administration | WordPress | Object-Oriented Programming Web Development | Social Media | User Experience Design | Data Analysis | Root Cause Analysis Adobe Creative Suite: Photoshop, Acrobat, InDesign, Illustrator, Premiere, XD (in progress) | Video and Photo Editing | Technical Writing, Editing, and Copywriting | Graphic Design | Painting | Clay Modeling Wireframing | Product Diagramming | Linux | Apache | Ubuntu | NginX | Microsoft Windows Console Apps Inventory Management | HIPAA | Epicor | PeopleSoft | SalesForce | QuickBooks | MedHub | Roadnet | MAS90 + MAS200 | SAGE | CIC + CRM | Paychex | ADP

Excellent Time Management | Stellar Customer Service | Tenacious Learner | Curious | Great Listener Problem Solver | Team Player | Self-Driven | Ethical | User Centered Designer | Pleasant | Kind

EDUCATION + DEGREES + CERTIFICATIONS

JAN 2019 - JUN 2020

Clark College, Vancouver, WA - AAT in Web Development, with honors

AUG 2009 - MAY 2011

Washington State University, Pullman, WA - BA in Humanities, magna cum laude Triple emphasis in Fine Arts, Music, and Anthropology; Minor in Sociology Certification in Professional Writing

May 2011

Washington State University, Pullman, WA - Certification in Professional Writing Proof of proficiency in technical and professional writing.

DEC 2019 - Credential ID mCCc-DTRs

Microsoft Technology Associate (MTA) - Software Development Fundamentals

education + degrees + certifications continued

AUG 2019 - Credential ID mwwz-uTYP

Microsoft Technology Associate (MTA) - Intro to Programming using HTML and CSS

AUG 2019 - Credential ID wCovR-48CC

Microsoft Technology Associate (MTA) - Intro to Programming using Python

JUN 2019 - Credential ID umAF-XLRq

Microsoft Technology Associate (MTA) - Database Administration Fundamentals

SEP 2017 - Credential ID 30-702005851

Rocky Mountain OSHA Outreach Training - 10-Hour General Industry, Safety, and Health

JUL 2019 - Credential ID 120815001

Washington State Liquor and Cannabis Board - Class 12 Mixologist Permit

EXPERIENCE

JAN 2018 - NOV 2018 - Vancouver, WA

Crafts Group, LLC - Marketing Assistant and Coordinator

Marketing assistant, trade show coordinator, program coordinator, Amazon storefront designer, and whatever else was needed for Knit Picks, Connecting Threads, and Artists Club.

- Directly supported the VP of Marketing and cover various positions/tasks as needed
- Trade Show Coordinator for all divisions; booth design and materials handler
- Product design and development; procurement and design implementation
- Proofing, Editing, and copyright for catalog, web, and print
- Use of Adobe Creative Suite to edit images and product patterns for web and download
- Inventory Management and Product Pricing Updates
- Designed and Launched the Amazon storefronts and assisted Amazon Director
- Independent Designer Program Coordinator for Knit Picks
- Supervised contract employees and managed projects
- Data auditing and database cleanup

OCT 2016 - DEC 2017 - Camas, WA

Tidland Winding and Slitting, a division of Maxess - Inside Sales II: Repairs Specialist

Started as a temp doing database cleanup, moved into sales and repairs, which meant designing and repairing the manufacturing shafts, brakes, chucks, and slitting machines that Tidland made for a variety of customers. Worked closely with engineering, R&D, and manufacturing.

- Quote customers for new Tidland brand products
- Quote repairs for slitting and winding division, with additional support to Maxcess products
- Managed workload of the repairs department and guided customers through basic repairs via phone and email
- Ran engineering calculations to ensure that products designed would meet safety standards with respect to customer specifications
- Support outside sales representatives in the field for sales and product troubleshooting

- Backup phone support and quoting coverage to other sales team members
- Improved turnaround times from months to days for repairs and increased department profitability by streamlining the repairs inspection and quoting process
- Audited and corrected the Maxcess customer database to ensure accurate customer information
- Assisted in the development of pricing and quote calculation tools
- Software and database design and testing (process input and use test)
- OSHA 10-Hr Certification and participation in the Safety Committee

JAN 2016 - OCT 2016 - Ridgefield, WA

Corwin Beverage Co. - HR, Payroll, and Benefits Coordinator

Human resources, payroll, and benefits coordinator for both Corwin Beverage and Kendall (prior to merger and new acquisitions). Supported HR Manager and acted as Union contact.

- Weekly and bi-weekly payroll; two companies with partially unionized employees
- Human Resources coordinator, processed paperwork and maintained employee files
- Pension Reporting and Audit Coordination
- Benefits Coordinator
- Recruiting and Hiring
- Processing of new hires and Onboarding/training of employees
- Administrative Support to Human Resources Manager and CFO
- Safety Coordinator for Safety Committee; maintained driver logs and safety checks
- Green Team: employee "green" initiative to improve the company's environmental impact

JUN 2014 - JAN 2016 - Portland, OR

Northwest Permanente, a division of Kaiser - Administrative Assistant

Administrative assistant to the Graduate Medical Education department of Northwest Permanente, the doctors and surgeons group of Kaiser Permanente NW.

- Created and maintained Standard Operating Procedures
- Digitized files, including HIPAA certification documents
- Managed student meal card programs
- Coordinated various technological access requests for medical students/residents/fellows
- Event and meeting planning
- Education and conference coordination
- Invoicing and cost auditing
- Data entry and database maintenance
- Purchasing and inventory management using PeopleSoft
- Administrative and scheduling support for department head and manager

OCT 2012 - JAN 2014 - Portland, OR

Encore Oils and SeQuential Pacific Biodiesel - Customer Service and Administrative Support

SeQuential is a leader in used cooking oil collection and biodiesel manufacturing.

- Primary customer service for 7000+ customers via phone, email, and in person
- Administrative support to the Human Resources and Operations/Logistics Managers
- Phone System Administration, IT troubleshooting and problem solving

- Scheduling for services including driver routing and dispatch
- Maintenance of Standard Operating Procedures and public correspondence templates
- Data processing and auditing
- Invoicing for charged services and backup for new account entry
- Outside Sales support
- Backup for other positions, as needed

AUG 2011 - APR 2012 - Portland, OR

Assumption Village Senior Living; Village Enterprises - Assistant Administrator

Assumption Village is a facility of Village Enterprises, a Portland based non-profit designed to house seniors in skilled, assisted, and independent living facilities. I was the assistant administrator, reporting directly to the administrator of the facility and managing facility operations. I began as the Executive Assistant to the CEO of Village Enterprises.

- Recruiting, Hiring, Onboarding, Human Resources Management
- Payroll, A/P, and A/R Processing
- Front Office Management and supervision of front desk staff
- Supervision of Housekeeping and Facilities Personnel
- Procurement and Vendor Contract Management
- Inventory Management and MSDS File Maintenance
- Facility Representative during Administrator leave
- Safety Coordinator and Employee Trainer
- IT Coordinator and Database Administrator
- Repairs Coordinator for Apartment Turnover
- Staffing Coordinator and Staff Floater
- Project Coordinator: helped design and complete "Village Cup" coffee shop in facility

NOV 2010 - JUL 2011 - Portland, OR

Bridgeport UCC - Office Administrator (temporary)

Bridgeport UCC is an all-inclusive religious organization that shares a facility with other faiths. I was their office administrator temporarily while completing my first Bachelor's degree.

- Business Office Management
- Accounting and Payroll
- Event Planning and Public Rental Coordination
- Administrative Support for Reverend and various Councils
- Weekly bulletin design and printing
- Supplies Ordering and Inventory Management

MAR 2010 - Washington, D.C.

Smithsonian Institution, National Museum of Natural History - Intern, Encyclopedia of Life

The Encyclopedia of Life program works to build global knowledge for life on earth. Through the Smithsonian Institution Museum of Natural History I was able to become an intern and contribute to the Encyclopedia's online database.

Research and compile information on give topic (tunicates)

- Verify use license for existing Smithsonian materials and information resources
- Post information on the Encyclopedia of Life website/database for public use
- Attend lectures and explore the "employee only" areas of the Smithsonian museum

APR 2008 - AUG 2009 - Vancouver, WA

Nutrition Now, Inc. + Supplement Sciences, Inc. - Administrative Assistant

Administrative support for Nutrition Now, Inc, Supplement Sciences, Inc., and Northwest Natural Products before they were purchased by Church and Dwight. Supported shipping/logistics, inventory management, manufacturing, QA, packaging, R&D, and sales.

- Shipping clerk and inventory control for shipping/logistics department
- Data entry for product transfers and order completion
- Special Order coordination for R&D and marketing
- Efficiency Reports for bottling rooms
- Updated and maintained Standard Operating Procedures
- Assistant to Logistics Manager and Production Manager
- Covered other departments in addition to my own for employee leave and support

JUN 2007 - FEB 2008 - Eugene, OR

Timeless Media Group - Office Assistant and Customer Service

Timeless Media Group specialized in the distribution of rare and hard to find media including DVDs and CDs. Sales were to the public and also to large international retailers.

- Customer service via phone, email, and in-person
- Data and Order Entry; Returns Processing
- Database Management and Inventory Maintenance
- Top Strip and Barcode Design and Printing
- Order and Returns Processing
- Invoicing and Accounting Support
- Training of new office staff
- Backup phone reception

JUN 2006 - JUL 2007 - Springfield, OR

Ross Stores, Inc. - Front End Supervisor

Front End Supervisor for Ross retail store in the Springfield Mall. Supervised employees, customer service, and returns.

- Customer Service, Cashiering, and Returns
- Supervision of retail team
- Inventory audits and pricing updates
- Cash Room Backup
- Display Coordination
- Phone Reception
- Product Tagging and Processing for Floor
- Loss Prevention